[Music]
foreign
so this is our
lesson 23 in terms of overall Tri-Cities
Tosca latest version 16 training
and this is lesson 8 in terms of
advanced
training
so in this lesson I'm gonna teach you
how can we use and implement the dynamic
ID by using
tricentistoska and also how can we use
and Implement explicit Name by using
price and discuss.com so I'm gonna give
you a complex scenario
and I'm going to teach you how to
automate that particular complex
scenario
where I have to use the dynamic ID and
explicit name to complete the automation
of particular that particular end-to-end
scenario okay
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos
thank you
okay so first what is dynamic ID
so in this lesson
I'm gonna teach you
how can you identify when a dynamic ID
should be used
and also
I'm gonna teach you how to create a
dynamic IDE in the properties of a
particular control
so the dynamic ID is a term for a value
of a property
on a module attribute that can
change during each distinct run
so basically it's an attribute so let's
say you are capturing a control
and you will be
identifying the unique properties right
of that particular control which needs
to be used
for a tasker to identify that particular
control uniquely okay so now you're
gonna add an additional property called
Dynamic ID
okay so I'm gonna teach you
uh shortly how can we create this
Dynamic ID okay and also this can be
achieved by using various Dynamic
expressions in Tasker so while creating
your Dynamic ID property you can achieve
the dynamic IDE by using a different or
various Dynamic expressions in task
okay so that is our first concept and
then our next concept is explicit name
so in this lesson I'm gonna teach you
how can you set the explicit name
configuration parameter on a module
attribute
and how to use this explicit name within
a test step
so explicit name is a configuration
parameter which can be added to your
module and it it allows a change in the
test step values name which reflects
technical identification
explicit name allows Tasker to steals
the object using index considering any
Dynamic changes
so as soon as you use explicit name in
the module attributes you can simply use
your index
okay while defining the test step
so you can utilize the explicit name
configuration parameter by going to step
that contains module attribute and
replacing the name with index number
okay so these are all the
um so definitions are whatever okay so
basically understanding explicit name
right so now let's jump onto the system
and see how can we use Dynamic ID and
the explicit name while automating the
real time scenario okay let's jump onto
the system
so this is my task called latest version
16. so first let us understand
how can we use this Dynamic ID and the
explicit name options by using Tasker so
first let us understand what scenario
do we need to automate
and
to automate that particular scenario we
would need to use these two options
called Dynamic ID and explicit names
okay so first so as you all know this is
our webshop where we'll be going to
apprehension shoes
right and then I'm gonna add blue jeans
to the cart once I add blue jeans to the
cart I'm going to agree to the terms and
conditions under shopping cart
check out right and then we are going to
place the order okay so this this end to
end automation we already done I already
explained you in many sessions and in my
previous session we also automated
a dynamic string so basically Dynamic
Expressions okay so you can visit my
previous session or any previous videos
okay so once you complete
your order right so in previous session
okay
what I explained you this order number
is so and so right so this order number
keeps changing
and this part of the string is static
and the last part of string is dynamic
and then V in in the previous session
what we did we validated this trend
static half one part of static string we
validated and the other part which is
dynamic we stored into a
buffer by using X buffer XB concept
right so I would recommend you guys to
visit my previous video to understand
what I'm talking about okay so then see
we compared this we validated the string
and we stored this order so once we
store the order now whatever the buffer
called order number we store this value
in the buffer called order number now
that buffer we need to use
in this particular session okay how I'm
gonna navigate to my profile okay
and then here click on orders
so if you see here it shows you your
entire order history
see if you see here this is my latest
order correct
and which has the corresponding details
and my previous to previous order is
this and then
and another order is this so this is how
your entire order history is being
displayed in this particular page so now
once I place the order I want to verify
if the corresponding order number
whatever it showed on the confirmation
page
will be listed here in the history or
not so
in my account under orders my latest
order number should be displayed here
so now how can you verify
your latest order is displaying in my
account under orders if you see here you
have lot of orders here right you you
need to you this and one more thing is
if you place another order this is going
to change now so now these controls are
not uniquely
identified these keep on changing
whenever you place a new one
correct so how can you
automate the scenario where I can verify
the latest order in my order history
okay this is where we need the dynamic
ID and the explicit name concept that we
need to use while automating your
scenario for that let's go back to our
presentation task
and then navigate to modules
under modules
navigate to webshop
click on invert
and then additional material
under additional material you will find
an empty module folder called access27
okay here now I need to scan
one of the container or div container
because see this is one div container
this is all one div container
and this is all another div container
and this is all another div container so
now I want to
scan these controls okay how right click
here
click on scan click on application
and select the application that you
would like to scan okay so this is the
application click on scan
now select the application that you
would like to scan click on scan
and here now
now select first div container if you
see these are all individual controls
but these individual controls are
residing under
container called div okay so now select
the div container
and then you need to also select your
order number
done
and I also would like to select order
total Li
and then I want to select capture the
details button
okay now go to Advanced View
and here
if you see here whatever we captured
right so if you you need to rename them
what is this div container this is
actually your order overview right let's
rename this as order
overview
and this one is your order number
and this is your order total
perfect done
so first
place your cursor or click on order
viewer View if you see here this order
overview property
you need to change the property because
inner text is empty right remove inner
text
select outer text
but this outer text
because this is my latest order
which has order number but this keeps on
changing right so now instead of using
this static
property you have to use a dynamic ID
so this is what
I'm talking about Dynamic ID using
Dynamic IDE for a control to identify
so using Dynamic IDE
in the properties of a particular
control okay here I am going to remove
entire this text and then I'm going to
put star here that means
this order over you div container
V is dynamic and I'm changing the
property of outer text by introducing a
dynamic expression with star
Okay now click ok
so now in the same way
go to order total and this also
you need to select your
visible inner text or outer text let's
select order text and here under outer
text you need to change here also the
order total might not be
always 18 right I want to convert this
to a dynamic ID
by removing the dynamic portion and by
introducing Dynamic expression
click OK and if you see here Dynamic
overview is not uniquely identified
that's correct because every div
container here has order number
colon and rest all star so now this is
not uniquely identified I know
so this can be your first order this can
be your second order this can be third
order whatever it may be right so if you
are not uniquely identifying this div
container that's what I need because I'm
going to use the explicit name
to uniquely identify this div container
so now you all understand how to use
your Dynamic IDE correct whenever you
are property of your control changes
okay so now let's rename this
demo
okay let's name this as webshop
order
details
and save this
so then let's close this
now if you go back to your modules now
this empty module has this Dynamic sorry
the order details right whatever we
captured the div container your order
number correct let's see the properties
div container order number order total
details okay whatever the properties
that we capture it has everything okay
now
to automate your test case
we need to introduce an explicit name
property
configuration property called explicit
name to this div container because this
div container is not uniquely identified
now
okay so let's what I want to do I want
to select this container
right click
and select your create configuration
parameter
and name this configuration parameter as
explicit
name without space
and
your explicit name
property value should be
true
and
introducing a new configuration
parameter called explicit name true
okay now save this
now let's see how can we use this
Dynamic ID so how can we use these
controls
which are
having Dynamic ID
and which is also having explicit name
property true okay so now let's go to
test cases
so if you remember we have automated our
uh in the previous session we have
automated Dynamic comparison scenario
right
so I would recommend you guys to go
through that particular video before you
watch this session because I'm gonna
use the same test case whatever we
automated in my previous session okay go
to the same test case
and expand your process
under process there is a folder called
check order
okay you need to
click on this check order
and here now you need to call the module
that just now we added this one right
webshop order details so now I'm gonna
insert
Ctrl T ADD test step okay I'm gonna
Grant a step
order details I'm going to add the
latest module whatever we captured
whatever we scanned
select that
and here now because we used explicit
name
in the configuration parameter for this
particular control
it's now our turn to use your index
because this particular container has an
explicit name you can directly specify
the index
okay I am naming that particular
module test case module as
hash one that means it's gonna refer
your first container
if I specify this as hash two it's gonna
refer your second div container so
because the latest order will be on the
top I want to specify this as 1.
and verify what I am going to verify I'm
going to verify the inner text will have
order number copy this
inner text
order number
colon space so whatever the buffer
whatever the buffer that we used to
store the confirmation number in my
previous session so as I told you you
have to visit my previous session where
we have stored the dynamic portion of
your confirmation number okay I'm gonna
call this same number here same buffer
see this is the order number
okay and then
because see this container will have
your order number and the order number
that is
displayed on screen once you place the
order and rest of the text so that's why
I'm using Dynamic expression here okay
order number colon space your order
number that you stored and dynamic
expression
so that's it so now save this
and here let's run this before you run
this particular test case you need to
log out
and close the web browser
and right click here now so you
understand right we have used
the dynamic ID
property
while capturing these controls for some
of the controls correct and then we used
explicit name
in the test case attribute
for that particular control
okay as an index okay now right click on
the test case and run in the scratch
book
so it should open your demo webshop
and then it is going to log in
provides the username password
go to operation shoes
and it is placing an order of blue jeans
25 items go to shopping cart now check
out
it's performing the checkout process
so once it checks out once you get the
confirmation number
in the previous session we were storing
that confirmation Dynamic part of your
string in buffer which is your order
number
and then see it stores that order number
so it's stored now order number and
store go to profile go to orders now
it's going to verify your first order
has the particular order number or not
so it's successful now
so if you go to your test results
so if you see the test results
your webshop order details see
it used your index
and it verified the first container see
verification was successful expression
order number
and the actual value and your expected
value is more both are same
right so everything is successful there
is no failure
okay hope you all understand how to use
your Dynamic IDE
while scanning the controls
and then how can you insert explicit
name to the control
called div overview and I'm gonna use
these
module in the test case and I'm gonna
specify index number itself directly to
your uh in the test case directly to the
test step itself and specifying that
number
index number
so that it refers to the corresponding
container okay hope you all understand
if you have any queries
leave your queries in the comment box
I'll try to respond to your queries
thank you please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank you